Honor Was Their Code.
Windtalkers is a war, action film directed by John Woo.
Joe Enders is a gung-ho Marine assigned to protect a "windtalker" - one of several Navajo Indians who were used to relay
messages during World War II because their spoken language was indecipherable to Japanese code breakers.
Sergeant Joe Enders, played by Nicolas Cage.
Private Ben Yahzee, played by Adam Beach.
Sergeant Eric Hjelmstad, played by Peter Stormare.
Corporal Charles Rogers, played by Noah Emmerich.
Pappas, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Harrigan, played by Brian Van Holt.
Windtalkers is a 2002 American war film directed and co-produced by John Woo, starring Nicolas Cage and Adam
Beach, with Peter Stormare, Noah Emmerich, Mark Ruffalo, and Christian Slater in supporting roles.
It is based on the real story of code talkers from
the Navajo nation during World War II.
The film was theatrically released in the United States by MGM Distribution Co.
on June 14, 2002, receiving mixed-to-negative reviews from critics and grossing just $76.7 million
worldwide against a production budget of $115 million, making it a box-office bomb.
The film explores themes of japan, world war ii, radio
transmission, marine corps, us army.